Good evening and welcome to our first
Investor meeting
for Blue Babylon Capital AB and Börstjänarfolket 2013 AB.
It's nice that so many have come here,
and tonight we will go through what has
happened since the last time we started the
new share issue,
where we are today and how the continuation
will look like.
There is a possibility to ask questions at
the end of the presentation, or it is
possible to ask questions during the time
when we will answer them at the end.
They will ask their question in a group
called Questions, I think, so that we can
see them.
My name is Henrik Hallenborg, and with me
tonight is our CEO Fredrik Swahn.
Good evening, Fredrik.
Good evening.
The technology works.
Yes, it works.
Yes, so let's go.
There are handouts in this program and the
investment letter that we sent
out earlier today.
If you didn't get it, you can listen to me
and I'll put it on the list.
We have also added the memorandum if we
have new listeners with us who have not seen
it before.
So, the near start of the trade.
Our first step was to get the name approved
by the company and
we initially used the name Babylon Capital AB.
But there was another company that had a
similar name, so we didn't get it approved.
We added a Blue, so it became Blue Babylon
Capital AB.
And it was approved quite quickly,
although the working name remains Babylon Capital.
Then, before Fredrik could become CEO,
the bank had to approve him following its
review.
This would take six weeks.
But only yesterday, after eight weeks,
Nordea finally approved Fredrik.
And that means that the last puzzle piece is
now in place and
we can begin trading in the CTA program
Arkad.
Kaptena can also complete the share register,
allowing us to move forward.
So how are things going with Kaptena, Fredrik?
Yes, but we have our contact person Veronica
there who is working on it
and she has put up all remaining
shareholders
and is just waiting for approval from the
company.
So,
yes, it should be a formality, I think.
Now we are on the rise with that too.
The share issue in Blue Babylon Capital raised
16 million
kronor,
which means that we passed the minimum
requirement of 1 million dollars, which was
necessary for us to trade these
trend-following models.
A smaller capital base would simply mean
fewer markets.
An account with $100 ,000 means that we can
be active in 4 -5
markets.
But now we can work with 40 -50 markets and
thus increase the chance
that we find a strong trend.
And the basis for our trend followings
is diversification, so that you are in as
many uncorrelated markets
as possible.
There is a limit somewhere at 50 -55
markets.
There are programs that have hundreds of
markets under trend followings,
But the correlation is getting higher and
higher when you get over 50 markets,
so that's why the limit is around 50
markets.
We are starting this in a very interesting
time, we can say worries.
It is usually the recipe for strong trends.
So we are bleeding macronutrients and
insecurity
in the oil.
A high oil price is easily transmitted on
other markets
due to the fact that it is more expensive to
produce.
This is negative.
It is important to understand that concern
can be a possibility for what
we do as trend followers.
We both buy and sell, so we don't need a
bull market, we don't need a market that
always rises to show results.
It builds as much on following the trend
down through blanks.
Perhaps the most important thing is that the
models we make do not build on
forecasts or that we predict the next trend.
We never know when a trend will come and
that is why we are looking for
diversification.
We don't know if it will be a favorable
market climate in
the future, but it is interesting.
Historically, we know that there have been
periods of crisis, worries and misery.
This has been trending and positive
for this type of investment.
Blue Babylon Capital has no trading performance to
be presented,
report yet, but Börstjänarfolket is already operating.
There was an increase of 7 .8 % in August.
It was related to a strong wave in crypto.
Last summer we went through the company and
the future
plans to just get to know the people and
that we now have a large exposure to
crypto.
If you miss this transition, it is recorded,
it's just that you hear off, so I'll
send it.
Especially the BitTensor that we are talking
about in this webinar, which we have a
fairly large position in, which we have
driven quite a long
way.
So the plans for this company in the future
is to simply reduce volatility
in the stock market and make it through a
better risk distribution.
And above all,
to reduce the altcoin exposure by buying
Bitcoin
and Arkad, which is the
trend-following program.
Bitcoin is for many very volatile, but
everything is relative.
So relative to altcoins,
Bitcoin is a little calmer.
It will not happen overnight,
It is a process that takes place in
connection with whether
we get a recovery in altcoins and a bull
market that can be used
to reduce volatility, simply
put.
If you miss that webinar, it is recorded.
We go through this in under an hour.
Henrik, I have a question here on the
previous slide from a listener.
What is Arkad? You mentioned it in the past,
but can you clarify a little bit more
so we all get on the train?
Yes, that was a very good question.
It is in Arkad that the capital is managed.
So the foundation is
that
Babylon Capital acts as a commodity pool
where investors
go together with a capital that is then
invested in the CTA
program Arkad.
The CTA program is managed by me, Henrik Hallenborg,
and it manages the capital of
Blue Babylon Capital,
but the possibility is also to invest
directly in the CTA program.
But then you need to come up with a million
dollars as the starting
point for it to work.
So if you invest one million, it can be more
advantageous to go directly
to the CTA program.
Yes, that's a good answer.
Arkad is not an existing external product; it is your
program that you have taken forward and
named after Arkad.
In connection with this, it is a newly
launched trend-following program
that is regulated.
The CTA program belongs to a regulated industry in the
US that is under the supervision of NFA and
CFTC.
I think we can refer to the memorandum where
there are recordings where we go
through this in more detail how the
situation looks
like.
It is also possible to call and take the
details on the phone.
So
when everything is done here and we get
started with the trade, we plan to bring in
more capital,
and we work with November 1 as the next time
to invest in this program
then it is good to increase the amount of
money available if
you want to increase the exposure
to this.
Or we can also take in new investors.
We are relatively small with 16 million in a
program.
Our goal here is to grow to create
a more stable company and we
see our network as an important part of it
all.
We encourage you to tell us about us for
people who
might be interested in diversifying the
portfolio for Managed
Futures.
We appreciate all the help that can
contribute to our growth.
It is also the case that a larger capital
base makes the company more effective
and robust.
If we get enough capital, we can take
advantage of it and pursue a stock-market listing
which would simplify investing, ownership and exiting.
Just now we are working on a website for
both Babylon Capital and
Börstjänarfolket.
On that site you will be able to follow the
development in graphs and statistics.
But we will also put the investment
philosophy behind both Babylon as a trend
follower and Börstjänarfolket.
and in the context that we bring in more
investors to Blue Babylon Capital,
we will hold meetings in Uppsala
and therefore new and existing investors.
We will run during the fall, but we have not
set the date yet
the most important thing is that we get
started here and then we take it as the next
step.
But already if you wake up, I go to Malaga
between the 24th and the 1st of
October
I am between Sottogrande and Nersja
You don't have to bring the golf clubs if
you want to meet and spend 4 hours
in the scorching sun
Or you can have a short lunch or a coffee
We
plan to hold these online meetings once a
month, first on Thursday every
month at 8 o 'clock.
The content will be results and questions,
and then I have put education as a point.
Therefore,
we are in this investment together and
it is not like investing in active funds.
We will have
ups and downs and volatility in the future.
The
education is about preparing yourself as an
investor on
how trend-following behaves, how the
investment moves, what is normal,
and that you thus also adjust the investment
size to these
swings so that you can sleep at night and
understand
I
thought we should start this education by
looking at the gold since
1980.
This is not the price of gold and we have no
share that
shows the value of how much it has
increased.
Because that's not what's interesting here.
There you can adjust the position size.
What's interesting here is how this trend
-following model has
performed over 46 years.
It's slightly upward, but
between 2000 and 2010 we had ten years of
weaker performance.
then followed for 10 more years, it went
very well
and it looks
like this when you look at other markets too
that our trend-following model that is
quantitative with exact rules for when we
are going to buy
when we are going to sell how much we are
going to do, the big position will be
As we have rules on this, we can simulate it
on historical data and see
how it would have gone.
That we have a ten -year period without
profit does not mean that we do not have it
in the portfolio.
It is often the case that the nearest ten
years do not look like the last ten.
If you just take the ones that have been
around for the past 10 years, you get
something that is less robust, I would say.
Do you take these markets with you?
I usually compare with Kakao, because it's a
very good example, when we started in
2012.
In 2013 we started in Orishanka,
and had done the simulation on Kakao,
which was about as much as gold was in 2010
in this graph,
it had not gone well at all with Kakao with
trend followings
but we traded anyway and Kakao has been for
the
last 15 years one of the markets that has
generated the strongest
trends
and most explosive, it looks a bit like
Bitcoin,
and it's about diversifying to models
that in the simulation have not shown good
results.
This also makes it more robust, secure
capital, you could say.
Therefore, we have not adapted to historical
data.
The more we adapt,
the worse the chance is that we survive
and that something changes that makes the
model
stop working completely.
The more you optimize the parameters
in the trend-following system,
the weaker the model becomes.
And then what we can take out from this
graph is that there will be spikes even
during times when it goes up a lot, when we
find a strong trend in a few years
and then it moves out there for many, many
years.
But if you combine this graph with more
markets,
so when gold is in a draw between 2000 and
2010, then maybe there is someone
else who has a spik -up in between and lifts
up the result.
Now we have come to the questions and would
like to tell you
more about trend followings and how it will
work in the
next online meeting.
How does it look? Fredrik, do we have any
more questions?
No, nothing more in the list.
I have a couple of questions that I have
saved from Meijl, it's
also good to hear from Meijl, a very good
question is how
much
Normally we don't use any stock,
normally we don't have any big positions, we
only have small losses as
we saw in the gold chart.
And then it looks on the deposit that we do
not use the capital
and it has happened that there have been
investors like
Managed Account and Managed Futures who are
fully aware of the deposit and
see that we do not use capital as a
part of the capital.
Then I have basically halved the account
because
it was assumed that we did not use it.
The account is a margin,
a safety for future business.
If we do exit before the physical delivery
happens,
there is no risk that we get a low local of
a raw material.
When a trend starts,
it is important to us how big the risk is.
If it turns down now, how much do we lose,
we lose a lot on the open profit,
but from the starting capital,
there
the risk is different depending on what risk
you choose, but somewhere
between 0 .5 % is a lot, in some cases up to
2%.
If we do not risk more than the interval,
then we can take as much leverage as we
want.
If it turns down, we have our stops that
make sure to close the
positions.
Sometimes we get a gap and the losses are
much more than expected.
But that is also a risk parameter that we
have in the
calculation, that it sometimes gets bigger.
But in these cases where we have a position
that is worth many
times more than it is worth,
it means that many positions have a profit
and are far from the three levels.
In this way, you build up a larger position
and use
high leverage.
If the customer then halves the account,
there is not enough capital
to build up these positions when you need
it.
In most cases, the capital just sits and
waits, there is no rush
at all.
And then when the trend comes, it is then
that the positions are
maximized, according to a quantitative
model.
I have some completing questions still.
To start with, when do you expect Babylon to
start?
And yes, if you had asked two months ago, I
would have said in one month.
And obviously it has not started, but there
has been a lot of
administration and waiting with the bank and
so on.
Now it is our hope and expectation that
Bolagsverket will be faster than
Nordea with its handling.
At the same time, Kaptena is preparing the
share register.
But I dare not say a date, but say a few
weeks up to a month.
What do you say Henrik?
Yes, everything is just about done.
So what I've been waiting for was
yesterday's message from Nordea, so you can start
doing your job.
And if you're fast,
it doesn't really depend on that.
It may not have much to do with the book,
but the important thing is that we get
started with trading.
It's not that far away, I think.
Good. It should not take too long,
and we are working on completing
everything we can,
so it should not be too far away.
Then we have a question,
are other algorithms used in trend tracking?
We
have a part of the capital in the so -called
quantum macro
that has the opportunity to go well
when we do not have any trends,
that's the thought behind it all.
But
at the same time, we don't want to disturb
the beauty of trendfuelling
and put too much in this quantum market,
because it is the more challenging part
to
perform.
The challenge is that these models have a
very
short lifespan,
generally not all of them.
I still have models that we developed ten
years ago that still work today.
But with a database of over 1 ,000
algorithms,
you don't really know which of them have
worked for 10 years that will work for the
next few years.
In short, we have a lot of capital in
QuantMacro,
but it is still in trend following as the
robust part lies.
The explanation for why it should continue
to work is not a simulation
or a
test.
What makes it robust and what we look at in
the gold is that you include markets
that have not gone so well.
And that we rely on the raw materials cycle
as the basis for this.
When the price is high, the production
increases and the consumption decreases.
Then it turns down and we get the opposite.
We also went through this in more detail in
the webinars for the memorandum.
And also the layout of QuantMac.
We'll talk about that.
Then we have one last question.
Do you use AI in your strategies?
Yes, it depends on the definition of AI.
I use
what happens when
traditional AI tools are the best way
to optimize something
to bring out something that generally does
not work in the future.
We have used neural networks and
had a development of these 1000 algorithms
that I mentioned, I have been working with
this for 10 years.
but it is self -developed, it is not an AI
service that is used for it.
Yes, then another question came up here.
Fifty markets—do you also trade individual
stocks or individual indices?
The
CTA program trades futures only, and futures are
the instruments
that we have as the basis for everything.
We can not trade stocks in the CTA program,
but the index, raw materials and
currencies.
It's nice that some questions have come up
at the end.
It seems that we have calmed down a bit.
As I said, in a month we will be back again
with new opportunities to ask all
questions.
Of course you can do that when you want to,
but it's fun when they come up like this
so everyone can hear the answers and
discussions around it.
I can conclude by talking
a little bit about stocks and trend
following.
When we apply these models in stocks,
we get a slightly different pattern.
It is not as effective.
In some stocks, of course, but then you have
to know which stocks to choose from.
In general,
the raw materials move more explosively and
the
index has not been a direct benefit to the
market for the
following trend.
The big edge is that when there
is a shortage of raw materials, there is a
very large
group of buyers who have to buy at any
price,
and producers.
This can create very powerful twists and
turns and sustainable trends if there
is an imbalance.
Then the market does not look back in the
same way that stocks do.
Stocks have a tendency to regulate directly.
A stock does not have the same cycle as we
see in raw materials.
There are many stocks that never turn again
in the
natural raw material cycle.
With
that,
I wish you all a nice evening and see
you in
Uppsala!